<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fausto&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://faustolazala.github.io/</link>
        <description>Recent content on Fausto&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faustolazala.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pick the right life partner</title>
        <link>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/pick-the-right-life-partner/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/pick-the-right-life-partner/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://faustolazala.github.io/p/pick-the-right-life-partner/partner.png" alt="Featured image of post Pick the right life partner" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most important choice you get to have is picking your life companion, and yet there’s not enough information on how to be good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society and our biological clock pushes us to rush this decision when we should be thinking it through, the same way we spend a whole year in high school trying to decide on the perfect career path to follow, and just then, we take roughly 4 years studying how to be good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time and dedication. We are focused on being good at what we do so we invest all this time aiming to achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;why-dont-we-do-the-same-when-choosing-our-significant-other&#34;&gt;Why don&amp;rsquo;t we do the same when choosing our significant other?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re blinded by love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s be real, love alone will not get you an epic relationship and following just your heart is a lazy way of settling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to be rational about the biggest decision of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping in mind that you’ll spend the rest of your life with the person you choose, what you’ll need to be looking for and at the same time what you must provide is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A really good friendship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A feeling of home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be determined to work it out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more to a good relationship, but for me these are the pillars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A relationship is a part-time job, you and your potential partner need to both understand this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication, as much as a cliché it sounds, can work out of every single fight you’ll get, because fighting is inevitable, but how you fight will dictate how good of a relationship you’ll have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all about compromise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a time where you can enjoy freedom, carve your own path and enjoy everything life has to offer, &lt;strong&gt;why would you choose to be half of something?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly it may feel like the math doesn’t add up, you’re giving up on your perfect life, everything you’ve worked for, but having a good life companion can improve every aspect of your already close to perfect relationship with yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of your life could be roughly 20,000 days so what better way to spend every single one of them with a person you enjoy being with, a friend, someone who you can trust, fun and respectful, but also somebody who understands that you are both individuals who decided to go through life together, you’re not bound to each other because you decided to get married, or because some cosmic energy made your paths cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you-get-to-choose&#34;&gt;You get to choose&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So choose wisely. Choose to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, every relationship is flawed and you can&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be perfect all the time, you can&amp;rsquo;t possibly get A+ in every single aspect of a relationship, but at least hope to excel at most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aim to be happy during the n-th dinner with your partner and know that you pick each other a thousands times because you enjoy every forgettable Wednesday spent together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to read more go visit &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://waitbutwhy.com/2014/02/pick-life-partner.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wait But Why&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s blog post on the subject. Since I read it a few years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on rationalizing most of my decision making and, in a very obvious way, it was my inspiration for writing this.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Retrocausality, can the effect come before the cause?</title>
        <link>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/retrocausality/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/retrocausality/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://faustolazala.github.io/p/retrocausality/causeeffect.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Retrocausality, can the effect come before the cause?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally we, as individuals, are coded to understand that everything happens for a reason. We experience time flowing in the forward direction, it&amp;rsquo;s how things work. One could argue there&amp;rsquo;s certain iterations of retrocausality in some type of precognitions if not all, but can it really happen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Retrocausality&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Retrocausality&lt;/a&gt; is a concept of cause and effect in which an effect precedes its cause in time and so a later event affects an earlier one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly, nothing we know can break causality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;maybe-were-moving-too-slow&#34;&gt;Maybe we&amp;rsquo;re moving too slow&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, if you could move faster than light, you could arrive at your destination before leaving. Does that mean you&amp;rsquo;ll be at two places at one? Not really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an observer it will appear as if you are in both places at the same time, but in reality the observer will see you at your departure point until the light of you leaving reaches him. In other words, you can only be at one place at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;it-doesnt-matter&#34;&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cause and effect only has a meaning on the bigger scale of things, we humans, are part of a bigger system controlled by time, so naturally, for us, that&amp;rsquo;s the only way things work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <link>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/hello-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://faustolazala.github.io/p/hello-world/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://faustolazala.github.io/p/hello-world/helena-hertz-wWZzXlDpMog-unsplash.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hello World" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, please enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
